Guide to the Kenneth J.Arrow Papers, 1939-2009
Kenneth J.Arrow Papers, 1939-2011
- Accession (2000-0222), 1977-1999, 2 Boxes
  - Chichilnisky-Wooders (2 of 2)
  - MacArthur Foundation - Economics
  - Monash University
  - International Economic Association Presidency
  - Minimum Wage Initiative
  - Lieberman Festschrift
  - Mitchell Madison
  - Milan, May 1995
  - Monash University Visit
  - Invitations Declined (1 of 2) (Box 2)
  - Invitations Declined (2 of 2)
  - Handbooks
  - Hong Kong
  - Hebrew University (1 of 2)
  - Hebrew University (2 of 2)
  - American Political Science Association (APSA) Meeting 1997
  - Guggenheim
  - Geanakoplos, John
  - Lin, Kuan Pin
  - Lewis, Alain A.
  - Huang, Peter H.
  - Math reviews
  - Papadopoulos, Nicholas Michael
  - Radner, Roy
  - Energy: The Next Twenty Years study group members
  - Ohashi, Isao
  - Kamoike, Osamu
  - Sheshinski, Eytan
  - Starrett, David A.
  - Correspondence G
  - Suppes forecasts
  - Kendall, Henry W.,; World Bank
  - Kurz, Mordecai
  - Office of Naval Research, official contracts data
  - Handbooks, Sheshinski
  - Hewlett Packard
  - Office of Naval Research, 1984-1985 budget
  - Jewish Community Federation
  - Rand
  - Stanford
  - Optimal Pricing of Natural Resources
  - Economics 280
  - Office of Naval Research, 1981-1982 budget
  - Office of Naval Research renewal, 1981-1982
  - Office of Naval Research Center (1 of 2)
  - Office of Naval Research Center (2 of 2)
  - Stan, Peter
  - Urban Institute
  - Office of Naval Research renewal, 1977-1978 project
  - Arrow/Hahn book negotiations (Holden-Day / Oliver Boyd)
  - Arrow/Hahn plans for revision
  - South Peninsula Campaign Cabinet
  - U.S. Council of Economic Advisers - Civilian Technology
  - Limits of Economic Rationality
  - Office of Naval Research report reproduction
  - Office of Naval Research annual proposal
  - Office of Naval Research II
  - Tulane Lecture
- Accession (2001-0004), 1980-2000, 2 Boxes
  This addition to Arrow's papers includes mainly professional correspondence, as well as some writings, referee reports, and conference and other materials, covering the years 1980-2000.
  This addition to the collection is RESTRICTED. Users must sign a release form to use any correspondence. See reference staff for more information.
- Accession (2002-0300), c. 1981-2002, 3 Boxes
  The addition (2002-0300) (1,125 items, 1.8 linear ft.; dated [ca. 1981]-2002) contains primarily incoming and outgoing correspondence and writings related to Arrow's professional interests.
- Accession (2004-0128), 1986-2004, 2 Boxes
  The addition (2004-0128) (550 items, 0.8 lin. ft.; dated 1986-2004) contains professional correspondence, public statements, itineraries, and related professional materials.
- Accession (2005-0065), 1941-2003, 5 Boxes
  The addition (2005-0065) (2,100 items; 2.8 lin. ft.; dated 1941-2003) comprises primarily reports, statements, and depositions prepared by Arrow as a consultant or expert witness in legal cases and for regulatory commissions. Among the companies involved are Microsoft, Shell Oil, Verizon, IBM, and ATT. Also includes diplomas, awards, and honorary degrees received by Arrow.
- Accession (2007-0214), 1978-2004, 1 Box
  The addition (2007-0214) (900 items; 1.5 lin. ft.; dated 1978-2004) includes reports, anti-trust court case files, Institute of Medicine materials, and other professional correspondence, articles, and statements.
  This addition to the collection may be RESTRICTED. Users must sign a release form to use any correspondence. See reference staff for more information.
  - Institute of Medicine: Financing (Box 1)
  - Referees' Reports
  - Pontifical Academy
  - Public Choice Society, 2001
  - Lang, S.
  - IOM Study Barat Report
  - IOM Study Pre-report Correspondence
  - IOM Study Post-report
  - Harsanyi, John
  - ABT Associates
  - Copper Case
  - Public Statements
  - Middle East
  - Pharmaceutical Anti-Trust
  - U.S. vs. Microsoft for Pro-Comp
  - Lewis, Alain, (2 folders)
  - Polyprapyleng Anti-Trust
  - Bell Atlantic-GTE Merger
  - Hewlett sustainability project
  - MacArthur General
  - National Medal of Science
  - Iteneraries
  - Journal of Mathematical Economics
  - MacArthur Social Interactions
  - Milan Hypothesis
  - NAS-CHR, 2000-2004
  - Rand Contracts
  - Stanford Research Institute
  - Game Theory Congress Bilbao, 2000
  - Chichilnsky
  - Nemetria
  - Sheshinski Fest
  - IOM: General Background
  - IOM-RBM Meeting, 2004 Sept. 9
  - IOM Under 5 Mortality Rates
  - IOM Global Fund
  - IOM Press
  - International Center for Theoretical Physics
- Accession (2008-0037), 1941-2007, 1 Box
  The addition (2008-0037) (375 items, 0.4 lin. ft.; dated 1941-2007 and undated) contains primarily professional correspondence regarding Arrow's early career; conference attendance; reviews, editorials, and other writing; and honorary degrees.
- Accession (2010-0045), 1990-2005, (1 Box)
  The addition (2010-0045) (300 items, 0.6 lin. ft.; dated 1990-2005) includes materials from Arrow's research on excess consumption and his various speaking engagements in Barcelona, Israel, and at the Office of Health Economics conference.
  - Beijer International Institute of Ecological Economics: Excess consumption, 2001-2004 (Box 1)
  - Beijer: Excess consumption II, 2003 (2 folders)
  - Ben-Gurion University of the Negev materials, 1990-1998
  - Barcelona conference, 1998-1999
  - Office of Health Economics (OHE) lecture, 2005
- Accession (2010-0182), 1984-2009, (1 box)
  The addition (2010-0182) (50 items; 0.2 lin. ft.) includes correspondence, speech drafts, and other materials regarding Arrow's travels and speaking engagements.
  - Abrams Lecture series speeches, Syracuse University, 1984-1991 (Box 1)
  - Amsterdam Royal Palace Foundation speech and event, 1996-1997
  - Federation of American Scientists, 1997
  - Tribute to Armen Alchian, International Society for New Institutional Economics conference, 2001
  - Antibiotic study, Resources for the Future, 2005-2007
  - Academe article on Arrow, 2006
  - American Political Science Association-Lippincott Award, 2009
- Accession (2011-0175), 1986-2011, (2 boxes)
  Includes correspondence with a number of colleagues and include birthday greetings, declined invitations to conferences, as well as nominations to the American Academy of Arts and Sciences. Additionally there are many public statements, some of these collaborations; as well as a number of reports by Alain Lewis of the University of California, Irvine.
  - Bergen, December 2001 (Box 1)
  - Birthday - 70th
  - Columbia 70th Birthday seminar reception
  - Birthday - 65th
  - Eightieth Birthday greetings
  - Public statements, 2000s, (3 folders)
  - Lewis, Alain, 1990s, (4 folders)
  - Lewis, Alain (Box 2)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences Nominations
  - AER Top 20
  - Bruno Memorial
  - Invitations declined, 2000s, (2 folders)
- Accession (2012-0115), (3 boxes)
  Files related to conferences and organizations in which Arrow was involved, including correspondence. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Arrow Prize (Berkeley) (Box 1)
  - Augier, Mie (Box 1)
  - Australia (Box 1)
  - Beijer-Asko, 2007-2008 (Box 1)
  - Cambridge University Press (Box 1)
  - Carey lecture (Box 1)
  - Conflict resolution (Box 1)
  - China (Box 1)
  - Cornell talk (Box 1)
  - Cutler-Amicas Curiae (Box 1)
  - Debreu Archives (Box 1)
  - Economics Dept. (Box 1)
  - ECAAR Kashmir (Box 1)
  - ECAAR Nuclear Statement (Box 1)
  - ECAAR Russia (Box 1)
  - Economists Against the Arms Race (Box 1)
  - Economists for Peace and Security (Box 1)
  - Employment Security (Box 1)
  - Federation of American Scientists (Box 1)
  - France-Stanford Center (Box 1)
  - Haavelmo Seminar (Box 1)
  - Handbook of Social Choice and Welfare, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Handbook of Social Choice and Welfare (Box 2)
  - Harcourt Preface (Box 2)
  - Harvard Degree (Box 2)
  - Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Mt. Scopus (Box 2)
  - Hotelling (Box 2)
  - Hurwicz Festival (Box 2)
  - IDDRI (Box 2)
  - IHEA (Box 2)
  - Institute of Medicine, antimalarial (Box 2)
  - Institutions and Development (Box 2)
  - Iraq (Box 2)
  - J: Miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Jerusalem, 2000-2010 (Box 2)
  - Jerusalem, New Director (Box 2)
  - Jerusalem School of Economic Theory (Box 2)
  - K: Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Karlin Conference (Box 3)
  - Karlin Memorial Resolution (Box 3)
  - Kurz, H. Letter on growth (Box 3)
  - Laffont Conference (Box 3)
  - Leverhulme Symposium (Box 3)
  - Levin paper (Box 3)
  - Micro Econ XX (Box 3)
  - Rational Choice and Humanities (Box 3)